OSCAR FABIO SALAZAR ROA

7195 South Terwillegar Dr NW, Edmonton AB CANADA | T6R 0P3 | oscarcanlx@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I consider myself to be a fast learner, self motivated, achievement- oriented and in search of new challenges on a professional level. With more than 15 years of professional experience, over time I have accumulated knowledge and business skills on the best practices in information and communication technology infrastructures, that allows me to bring a diverse technical know-how set to improve the operations of any company.

EXPERIENCE

IT SUPPORT ENGINEER SUMMIT WIRELINE INC (LLOYDMINSTER, AB – CANADA)

JAN 2020 - CURRENT

- Administration, implementation, support, maintenance and monitoring of technological services (Printing, File Sharing, Directory, Internet, Mail, Web, Applications, Data Bases, Backup) on premises and on Microsoft 365 Cloud.
- Administration, execution and control of backup and information recovery.
- Provide technical support and troubleshooting over all technological platform to guarantee the operational business continuity.

TECNOLOGICAL PROJECTS SPECIALIST

DEC 2017 - DEC 2019

TODOSISTEMAS STI - OUTSOURCING BANK BANCAMIA (BOGOTA - COLOMBIA)

- Architecture, design, planning, implementation and maintenance of the technological infrastructures.
 (Servers, Networking, Storage, Security, High availability, Data Bases, Backup) on premises and AWS Cloud for the digital transformation and innovation projects of Bank Bancamia.
- Development of Capacity Planning, technological investment plan and budget requirements for the execution of projects.
- Preparation and execution of workloads and stress test schemes to measure the capabilities of applications and services before being implemented in a production environment.
- Remediation of vulnerabilities and technological security issues, detected by the Ethical Hacking studies and analyzes carried out on the projects.

TECHNOLOGICAL INFRASTRUCTURE SPECIALIST CRIPTOTEC SISTEMAS, C.A (CARACAS – VENEZUELA)

SEPT 2010 - OCT 2017

- Administration, implementation, support, maintenance and monitoring of technological services.
 (Printing, File Sharing, AD DS Directory, Internet, DNS, DHCP, Mail, Web, Applications, Data Bases, Backup) in Windows and Linux server's environment and networks under the CISCO platform.
- Administration and support of Network firewall, VPN and security platform Fortinet (FortiGate, VPN).
- Evaluate operations and define contingency and recovery processes of the technological infrastructure, in order to establish parameters to guarantee the operational continuity of the company.

• Implementation, administration, execution and control of backup policies, backup processes and information recovery.

TECHNOLOGICAL PROCESS SPECIALIST ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT BANK OF VENEZUELA (BANDES) (VENEZUELA-URUGUAY)

- I was carrying out Project management functions in the Adaptation of the Technological Platform of BANDES Project in conjunction with approximately 140 professionals from various areas of the IBM.
- Design, Adaptation, Update and implementation of the BANDES technological platform in the localities of Venezuela and Uruguay.
- Including, construction of the main and alternate data center, disaster recovery plan, windows and banking distributed servers' platform (core banking BANTOTAL) and BackOffice (ERP-K2B).
- CISCO network platform, video conferencing, storage area networks (SAN), robotics for data backup, recovery, interconnection and asynchronous replication with high availability between the data centers of Venezuela and Uruguay.

TECHNOLOGICAL INFRASTRUCTURE CONSULTANT JAN 2005 – MAR 2007 TREASURY BANK OF THE GOVERNMENT OF VENEZUELA (CARACAS – VENEZUELA)

- I was carrying out the Project management functions for Treasury Bank in the construction of the entire technological platform project in conjunction with approximately 100 professionals from various areas of the IBM company.
- Design, Implementation and commissioning of the entire technological platform.
- Including Construction of the Main and Alternate Data Center, Disaster Recovery Plan, Banking Server Platform (IBS Core Banking) and Distributed (ERP-SAP), Network Platform and IP Telephony.
- Data Storage, Backup and Recovery Platform, Operating Software, High Availability, Transactional Switch,
 ATM Network, Front-End and Back-End Office Platform.

TECHNOLOGICAL INFRASTRUCTURE CONSULTANT JAN 2001 – DEC 2004 MINISTRY OF FINANCE OF THE GOVERNMENT OF VENEZUELA (CARACAS – VENEZUELA)

- Analyze resources, files and storage media used by the operations of the data center, in order to evaluate their execution time, process and response, coordinating the workload distribution.
- Implement technological policies for the institute, in order to ensure operational continuity and guarantee the efficient use of resource.
- Provide advice and support to ensure that the institute's information and communication technology services
 are executed in an agile, timely and reliable manner, under strict standards of control and security, in
 accordance with the regulatory provisions on the matter.
- Verify the activities of the production area and production control, in order to issue suggestions for the control, regulations and security, both logical and physical, of the processes of the data center.

APR 2007 - MAR 2010

- Architecture, implementation, administration, support, maintenance and monitoring of technological services.
 (Printing, File Sharing, AD DS Directory, Internet, Mail, Web, Applications, Data Bases, Backup) in servers under Microsoft Windows operating systems and networks under the CISCO platform.
- Define parameters for the contingency and disaster recovery plans of the technological infrastructure to guarantee the operational business continuity.

EDUCATION

- PROJECT MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST
 Unitec University, Bogota Colombia
- COMPUTER ENGINEER
 Alejandro de Humboldt University, Caracas Venezuela

SKILL & EXPERTISE

- Wide experience in architecture, design, planning, implementation, administration, maintenance, support, migration of multi-business, on premises, distributed, on cloud information and communication technology infrastructures.
- Experience in the Implementation, administration, maintenance and migration of the main services and workloads on the Cloud, AWS (EC2, ELB, S3), Microsoft Azure (Azure Active Directory, Virtual Machines, Virtual Networks, Azure Storage), Microsoft 365 (Directory, Exchange Online, SharePoint Online, OneDrive).
- Knowledge in administration and support of the Cisco Networks platform (Routing, Switching, Firewall).
- Experience in administration and support of Storage area networks (SAN) platforms and Backup with Robotic Automatic Libraries.
- Knowledge in administration of Network firewalls, VPN and security platforms Fortinet (FortiGate, VPN).
- Extensive experience in the implementation, administration, support, maintenance and migration of Microsoft Windows Server 2008, 20012, 2016 platforms, as well as services and roles (AD DS, AD FS, DHCP Server, DNS Server, File and Storage Services, Hyper -V, Web Server IIS, Windows Server Update Services WSUS, Microsoft Windows Failover Cluster WFC, Group Policy.
- Experience in Implementation, administration, maintenance of the Microsoft Exchange Server 2007, 2013 Mail
 Platform.
- Experience in implementation, administration, maintenance and support of Hypervisors and Virtualization
 Platforms Qemu/KVM, Proxmox VE, Microsoft Hyper-V and VMware.
- Experience in implementation, administration, maintenance and support of Microsoft SQL Server 2008, 2016
 Databases.
- Experience in implementation, administration, maintenance and support of Linux Ubuntu, RedHat, Centos servers (Firewall, DNS, DHCP, Apache, Nginx, MariaDB).
- Skills and knowledge for the formulation, planning and execution of technological projects.
- Budget planning and Capacity Planning.
- Development of agile technological infrastructure projects under the SCRUM methodology.

SEMINARS / WORKSHOP / TICKETS

- > Agile methodologies workshop
- ➤ Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Windows Server 2012 2016
- > Core Banking Infrastructure e-IBS
- > iSeries Replication technology IASP
- > ITIL V3 Foundation for IT Service Management
- Fast Track Certified Information System Security Professional CISSP
- > Fast Track Cisco Associate certifications CCNA
- Project Planning, Evaluation and Execution
- Standard First Aid W/ CPR
- Class 4 Driving License

AWARDS AND ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS

- Acknowledgment for an Outstanding Contribution to the Sincor Project (San Diego de Cabrutica Venezuela).
- Order of Merit at Work by the Ministry for the work and social security of the Government of the Republic of Venezuela Award (Caracas – Venezuela).
- Acknowledgment for an Outstanding Contribution to the Adaptation of the Technological Platform of BANDES
 Venezuela and Uruguay Project (Caracas Venezuela).
- Acknowledgment for an Outstanding Contribution to the Implementation of the Technological Platform of Treasury Bank Project (Caracas – Venezuela).